<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Institute of Marine and Coastal Sciences (IMCS), Rutgers University</origin>
				<pubdate>20081225 (GIS date)</pubdate>
				<title>Boundaries of the Jacques Cousteau National Estuarine Research Reserve (JC NERR)</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>New Brunswick, NJ</pubplace>
					<publish>CRSSA - Rutgers University</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>http://crssa.rutgers.edu/</onlink>
				<lworkcit>
					<citeinfo>
					</citeinfo>
				</lworkcit>
				<ftname Sync="TRUE">JCNERRboundary_2008</ftname></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<supplinf>Jacques Cousteau National Estuarine Research Reserve Management plan
</supplinf>
			<langdata>english</langdata><abstract>Boundary for the Jacques Cousteau National Estuary Research Reserve. The JC NERR consists entirely of public lands already possessed by the state, federal, or local government. The following criteria were used in the selection of the JC NERR boundaries:

a. Minimum amount of development and population in upland watershed and coastal/estuarine area.

b. Maximum amount of watershed protection in the form of public open space and multilevel state regulatory programs for private lands (e.g.,Pinelands Commission regulation).

c. Maximum amount of coastal/estuarine wetlands protection in the form of public open space (e.g., fish and wildlife management areas, park and forest lands, refuge space).

d. Maximum amount of diversity in rare plants, animals and natural communities which interact with the estuarine zone.  Diversity provides for contact with all representative trophic levels within the integrated ecosystem.  The inclusion of many habitat types allows for a full range of comparative research and education activities.

The JC NERR boundary was delineated to incorporate the Mullica River upriver to the head of tidal influence and down river to include all of Great Bay (Figure 5).  The JC NERR boundary extends north to include the adjacent waters and marshes of Little Egg Harbor to include submerged aquatic vegetation habitats (i.e., extensive beds of eelgrass, Zostera marina) that are largely absent from Great Bay proper.  The proposed boundary extends south to the important migratory waterfowl habitats contained in the Brigantine portion of the Forsythe National Wildlife Refuge and adjacent State Fish &amp; Game Management lands.  The tributaries of the Mullica River including Bull Creek, Wading River, Bass River, Landing Creek, and the Nacote Creek are included to the limit of tidal influence. The boundaries for the JC NERR were designed to the greatest extent possible to compromise a natural ecological unit.  The JC NERR boundaries encompass a core area of contiguous wetlands, riparian habitats, and portions of open water in Great Bay.  These boundaries contain a highly productive system supporting a rich diversity of activities including recreation such as fishing and boating, as well as research studies by Rutgers University (since 1972), Richard Stockton College of NJ, the Pinelands Commission, and other institutions.

Because estuaries receive inputs from the adjacent oceanic margin, the boundaries of the JC NERR extend seaward into the Atlantic Ocean approximately 3 miles to include the LEO-15 on the inner continental shelf.  One obvious reason for considering this oceanic area is the importance of organic and inorganic exchanges within the water column and at the sediment interface, and opportunities to evaluate the significance of the oceanic contributions to the maintenance of the estuarine system.  The LEO 15 site is designated as a 2.79 km offshore research area and is listed on all navigation charts and notices to mariners. As a result of a proposal to construct a power plant on the continental shelf in the 1970's, a variety of baseline environmental monitoring studies were conducted to characterize the physical environment, along with investigations designed to compare change among fish and shellfish communities.  

In Great Bay proper, with the exception of the small communities (i.e., small population size) of Mystic Island and Tuckerton extending for less than 3,000 m along the margin of the Bay, the aquatic boundary is in a near pristine state.  A handful of marinas occur outside of Mystic Island, but their spatial impact is small within the overall scale of the JC NERR.  This characteristic is particularly beneficial to compare the long term processes related to estuarine quality in other nearby locations.  For example, the adjacent waters and shoreline of Little Egg Harbor have experienced greater human pressure with the lagoonal development of Beach Haven West and the developed portions of Long Beach Island.  Thus, the MRGB estuary can provide baseline data for evaluating modification and recovery programs at other sites.

The National Estuarine Research Reserve at Mullica River - Great Bay, New Jersey, vector coverage was created in Arc/Info (version 7.*) using existing digital information and ancillary GIS data.  Originally, the MRGB NERR geographic information system database was created and updated over the timeline of the project by deliniating reserve boundaries on United States Geological Survey 7.5 minute quadrangles, then subsequently digitizing the boundaries in Arc/Info (version 6.*).  In addition, Landsat Thematic Mapper (30 meter ground resolution) satellite remote sensing data was integrated into these boundaries for updating the land cover aspect of the database (i.e. coastline differnces). In 1998, after the final 1997 approval of the MRGB NERR, the GIS database was updated in order to standardize the reserve boundaries to existing digital information such as open space/public land, roads, and coastlines created by New Jersey and US Federal agencies.  The standarization of the reserve boundaries allows users of the data to integrate the MRGB NERR vectors with other regional GIS layers with greater positional accuracy.

2008 update to the JC NERR Boundaries: Properties that were adjacent to the previous JCNERR_boundaries that were purchased by the New Jersey Conservation Foundation were selected for inclusion into the updated 2008 JCNERR boundaries. They include

Rudolph 1 property 
Rudolph 2 property
Lee property
Hanselman Clark property
Bear Creak property

Properties were merged and then added to the previous property boundary using Arc GIS 9.3.  Since some of the properties were allready subdivided right of ways were including within the new JC NERR boundaries. Contact Scott Haag for more details.</abstract><purpose>(NOAA Mission Statement) "The National Estuarine Research Reserve System (NERRS) is a protected areas network of federal, state, and local partnerships.  The program was created with the 1972 passage of the Coastal Zone Management Act.  Through linked programs of stewardship, education, and research, the NERRS enhances informed management and scientific understanding of the Nation's estuarine and coastal habitats."  The Jacques Cousteau National Estuarine Research Reserve at Mullica River - Great Bay was designated in October of 1997.</purpose></descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<rngdates><begdate>1992</begdate><enddate>2001/1/1</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>As needed</update></status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>
-75.487931</westbc>
				<eastbc>
-73.922827</eastbc>
				<northbc>
41.350282</northbc>
				<southbc>
38.992754</southbc>
			</bounding>
			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">529166.250000</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">569940.000000</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4359040.500000</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">4392933.000000</topbc></lboundng></spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekey>oceans</themekey>
				<themekey>boundary</themekey><themekey>national estuarine research reserve</themekey><themekey>Jacques Cousteau NERR</themekey><themekey>Open Space</themekey><themekey>Estuary</themekey><themekey>Mullica River</themekey></theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>none</placekt>
				<placekey>Barnegat Bay</placekey>
				<placekey>Little Egg Harbor</placekey>
				<placekey>Ocean County</placekey>
				<placekey>New Jersey</placekey>
				<placekey>Mullica River</placekey><placekey>Great bay</placekey><placekey>Jacques Cousteau National Estuary Research Reserve</placekey></place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkt>none</tempkt>
				<tempkey>2008</tempkey>
			</temporal>
			<theme><themekey>Boundary</themekey><themekey>coastal</themekey><themekey>Preserved land</themekey><themekey>Rutgers University</themekey><themekey>Jacques Cousteau National Estuarine Research Reserve</themekey></theme></keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Scott M. Haag</cntper>
					<cntorg>Institute of Marine and Coastal Sciences (IMCS)</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>Environmental and Natural Resource Sciences Building</address>
					<address>14 College Farm Road</address>
					<city>New Brunswick</city>
					<state>NJ</state>
					<postal>08901-8551</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>732-932-1582</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>732-932-2587</cntfax>
				<cntemail>scotth@crssa.rutgers.edu</cntemail>
				<hours>M-F 8.30am - 4.30pm EST USA</hours>
				<cntinst>e-mail is the fastest way to contact Scott Haag</cntinst><cntpos>Field Researcher</cntpos></cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<datacred>Jacques Cousteau National Estuarine Research Reserve (JC NERR)
Institute of Marine and Coastal Sciense (IMCS), Rutgers University</datacred>
		<secinfo>
			<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
		</secinfo>
		<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</native>
		<crossref>
			<citeinfo>
				<onlink>www.jcnerr.org</onlink>
				<origin>JCNERR staff</origin><pubdate>Unknown</pubdate><title>JCNERR Profile Report</title><origin>Michael J. Kennish</origin></citeinfo>
		</crossref>
		<natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform><useconst>Data set is not for use in litigation.
 
While efforts have been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the state of the art, Rutgers University cannot assume liability  for any damages, or misrepresentations, caused by any inaccuracies in the data, or as a  result of the data to be used on a particular system. Rutgers University makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</useconst></idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
		</attracc>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>           The positional accuracy and precision of this database is based on the source data from which this coverage was created.  The source data used are from the New Jersey Deparment of Environmental Protection's (NJDEP) open space/public land and coastline Arc/Info coverages and also (very small portion) from the United State Geological Survey's (USGS) hydrological digital data.  The source scales are 1:24,000.</horizpar></horizpa>
			<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>na</vertaccr></vertacc>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection</origin><pubdate>updated</pubdate><title>New Jersey State Owned Open Space</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><onlink>http://www.state.nj.us/dep/gis/stateshp.html#STOPEN</onlink></citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>1992</begdate>
							<enddate>2008</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr></srctime>
				<srcscale>1/24,000</srcscale><typesrc>online</typesrc><srccontr>New Jersey Deparment of Environmental Protection's (NJDEP) open space/public land and coastline Arc/Info coverages.

http://www.state.nj.us/dep/gis/stateshp.html#STOPEN</srccontr></srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Institute of Marine and Coastal Sciences, Rutgers University</origin>
						<origin>Center for Remote Sensing and Spatial Analysis, Rutgers Unversity</origin>
						<title>Assessment of the health and distribution of Submerged Aquatic Vegetation from Little Egg Harbor, New Jersey</title>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>digital tape media</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<mdattim>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>1999</caldate>
							</sngdate>
							<sngdate>
								<caldate>2000 processing completion</caldate>
							</sngdate>
						</mdattim>
					</timeinfo>
				</srctime>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<proccont>
					<cntinfo>
						<cntperp>
							<cntper>Richard G. Lathrop</cntper>
							<cntorg>Center for Remote Sensing and Spatial Analysis (CRSSA), Cook College - Rutgers University</cntorg>
						</cntperp>
						<cntpos>Director</cntpos>
						<cntvoice>732-932-1582</cntvoice>
						<cntemail>lathrop@crssa.rutgers.edu</cntemail>
					</cntinfo>
				</proccont>
				<procdesc>
    The National Estuarine Research Reserve at Mullica River - Great Bay, New Jersey, vector coverage was created in Arc/Info (version 7.*) using existing digital information and ancillary GIS data.  Originally, the MRGB NERR geographic information system database was created and updated over the timeline of the project by deliniating reserve boundaries on United States Geological Survey 7.5 minute quadrangles, then subsequently digitizing the boundaries in Arc/Info (version 6.*).  In addition, Landsat Thematic Mapper (30 meter ground resolution) satellite remote sensing data was integrated into these boundaries for updating the land cover aspect of the database (i.e. coastline differnces). In 1998, after the final 1997 approval of the MRGB NERR, the GIS database was updated in order to standardize the reserve boundaries to existing digital information such as open space/public land, roads, and coastlines created by New Jersey and US Federal agencies.  The standarization of the reserve boundaries allows users of the data to integrate the MRGB NERR vectors with other regional GIS layers with greater positional accuracy.  

   Basically, the 1998 digital boundary coverage update involved "clipping" New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP) open space/public land polygons by New Jersey Department of Transportation (NJDOT) roads and NJDEP coastline data.  Also, if sedge islands were absent from the NJDEP coastline data, USGS 24k hydrological digital data were then included/added to the updated coverage.  Also, some on-screen digitizing for a very small portion of the data using the 1995 color-infrared one-meter digital orthophotography as a "back drop" aided the update process, however, the latter method was not prevalent throughout the MRGB NERR update.

   Another key aspect of the coverage update was the accuracy of the polygonal attributes.  Four items in the coverage's polygon attribute table were added then given their appropriate categorical values.  Below lists the four attributes and their respective descriptions:

   1. STATUS.CODE (2,2,I): A numeric code which identifies the polygons which are in the MRGB NERR.  A value of '1' is land within the reserve and '2' is water in the reserve.  A zero polygon signifies that it is not part of the reserve.

   2. STATUS (4,4,C): Status of a poly: whether or not it is in the reserve.

   3. NAME (64,64,C): The name of the polygon (Example: Edwin B. Forsythe National Wildlife Refuge).

   4. TYPE (32,32,C): The type of open space/public land (Example: Wildlife Management Area).

Please note that the water within the reserve is simply given the title of NERR water and is not broken down into more detailed categories (Example: Mullica River).

* Also, the projection of this coverage is UTM, the spheroid is GRS1980, and the datum is NAD83 (units: meters).
</procdesc></procstep>
			<procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">\\ad-rsc\data\databank\crssa\metadata\njgin\bbaysav96_99_fgdc</srcused><date Sync="TRUE">20081215</date><time Sync="TRUE">12444600</time></procstep><procstep><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Scott M Haag</cntper><cntorg>JCNERR</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Field Researcher</cntpos><cntvoice>732-932-1582</cntvoice><cntfax>732-932-2587</cntfax><cntemail>scotth@crssa.rutgers.edu</cntemail><hours>9:00 - 5:00</hours><cntinst>E-mail is best</cntinst></cntinfo></proccont><srcused>New Jersey Conservation Foundation protected lands</srcused><procdesc>2008 update to the JC NERR Boundaries 

Properties that were adjacent to the previous JCNERR_boundaries that were purchased by the New Jersey Conservation Foundation were selected for inclusion into the updated 2008 JCNERR boundaries. They include

Rudolph 1 property 
Rudolph 2 property
Lee property
Hanselman Clark property
Bear Creak property

Properties were merged and then added to the previous property boundary using Arc GIS 9.3.  Since some of the properties were allready subdivided right of ways were including within the new JC NERR boundaries. Contact Scott Haag for more details.





</procdesc><procsv>Arc GIS 9.3</procsv><procdate>2008</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">C:\ACE_GIS_projects\NERRS_GIS_Data\Jacques_Cousteau\JCNERRboundary_2008</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20090513</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">10190900</proctime></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">Z:\MB7\Projects\SITB\NERRS_Clement\CDMO Transfer\Bundled_boundaries\Bundled_boundaries\JQCNERRboundary_2008</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20091014</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">09271500</proctime></procstep></lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm Name="JCNERRboundary_2008">
				<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>74</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>Label point</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>887</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>931</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>4</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<esriterm Name="JCNERRboundary_2008"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">194</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<planci>
					<plance>coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres>0.000133</absres>
						<ordres>0.000133</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu>meters</plandu>
				</planci>
				<gridsys><gridsysn Sync="TRUE">Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone Sync="TRUE">18</utmzone><transmer><sfctrmer Sync="TRUE">0.999600</sfctrmer><longcm Sync="TRUE">-75.000000</longcm><latprjo Sync="TRUE">0.000000</latprjo><feast Sync="TRUE">500000.000000</feast><fnorth Sync="TRUE">0.000000</fnorth></transmer></utm></gridsys></planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
			<cordsysn><geogcsn>Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM)</geogcsn><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_18N</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>
		<vertdef><altsys><altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum><altunits>meters</altunits></altsys></vertdef></spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="JCNERRboundary_2008">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">194</enttypc><enttypl Sync="TRUE">JCNERRboundary_2008</enttypl></enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of polygon in square meters</attrdef>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">18</attwidth><attalias Sync="TRUE">AREA</attalias><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">5</atnumdec></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Perimeter of polygon in meters</attrdef>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">18</attwidth><attalias Sync="TRUE">PERIMETER</attalias><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">5</atnumdec></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">JCNERR_</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">JCNERR_</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">11</attwidth><attrdef>unique id</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">JCNERR_ID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">JCNERR_ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">11</attwidth><attrdef>unique id 2</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">STATUS_COD</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">STATUS_COD</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><attrdef>A numeric code which identifies the polygons which are in the MRGB NERR.  A value of '1' is land within the reserve and '2' is water in the reserve.  A zero polygon signifies that it is not part of the reserve.</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">STATUS</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">STATUS</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><attrdef>Status of a poly: whether or not it is in the reserve.</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">NAME</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">NAME</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">64</attwidth><attrdef>The name of the polygon (Example: Edwin B. Forsythe National Wildlife Refuge).</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">TYPE</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">TYPE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">32</attwidth><attrdef>The type of open space/public land (Example: Wildlife Management Area).</attrdef></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">MAP1</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">MAP1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">JCNERR</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">JCNERR</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">16</attwidth><attrdef>jcnerr if inside the jcnerr boundary</attrdef><begdatea>2008</begdatea></attr></detailed>
		<overview>
		</overview>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Center for Remote Sensing and Spatial Analysis (CRSSA), Cook College - Rutgers University</cntorg>
					<cntper>Scott M. Haag</cntper></cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<city>New Brunswick</city>
					<state>NJ</state>
					<postal>08901-8551</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>732-932-1582</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>732-932-2587</cntfax>
				<hours>M-F 8.30am - 4.30pm EST USA</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<transize>0.743</transize>
					<dssize Sync="TRUE">0.996</dssize></digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<accinstr>Downloadable data</accinstr>
						<oncomp>http://crssa.rutgers.edu/projects/runj/sav/</oncomp>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>none</fees><ordering>Available online</ordering></stdorder>
		<resdesc Sync="TRUE">Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure  that these data are accurate and reliable within limits of the state of the art,  Rutgers University will not assume any liability for damages caused by any inaccuracies in these data, or failure in their use.  Rutgers University makes no warranty, expressed, or implied, nor does the act of distribution, or sale of, constitute such a warranty.  </distliab><custom>available online</custom></distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>2009/1/1</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Jacques Cousteau National Estuarine Research Reserve</cntorg>
					<cntper>Scott M. Haag</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>Environmental and Natural Resource Sciences Building</address>
					<address>14 College Farm Road</address>
					<city>New Brunswick</city>
					<state>NJ</state>
					<postal>08901-8551</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>732-932-1582</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>732-932-2587</cntfax>
				<hours>M-F 8.30am - 4.30pm EST USA</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
		<metsi>
			<metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
		</metsi>
		<metextns>
		</metextns>
		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>
	<Esri><ModDate>20090513</ModDate><ModTime>10500600</ModTime><CreaDate>20091014</CreaDate><CreaTime>09271500</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20090513</SyncDate><SyncTime>10500600</SyncTime><MetaID>{61D8B149-CED4-4D2D-AE20-0D81ED2DD74A}</MetaID></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20090513</mdDateSt><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\AAMB-L-1766140\C\LandCover\forCDMO\JAC\Boundaries\Reserve_Boundaries\JQCNERRboundary_2008</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.996</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">JCNERRboundary_2008</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">529166.25</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">569940</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">4392933</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4359040.5</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-74.661355</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-74.184404</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">39.685734</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">39.378009</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="JCNERRboundary_2008"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">194</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_18N</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo></metadata>
